Jad Mukbel

jadmukbel@gmail.com | (951)-314-4755 | linkedin.com/in/jad-mukbel | Corona, CA

SKILLS

- Languages: C++, Python, Java, Scala
- Proficient in Big Data Management, Data Analysis and Processing Packages, Data Structures, Object
 Oriented Design, Version Control Systems, & Agile Methodologies
- Strong problem-solving and analytical skills.
- Extensive corporational and organizational experience.

RELEVANT PROJECTS

Tamabotchi (Python) - A bot embedded within Discord utilizing its API. A shared virtual pet among a server in which members contribute to nurturing the personalized pet through the bot's extensive features.

Wildfire Analysis (Scala) - Developed a machine learning model to predict fire intensity based on analyzed spatio-temporal features of a specified fire. Trained and tested on a wildfire dataset in California.

Analysis of Academic Imposter Syndrome (Python) - Utilizing data analysis methods and techniques, collected and analyzed real-student data to assess correlations between student demographics and experience with perception of imposter syndrome.

EXPERIENCE

Southern California Director, Board of Directors - MSA West

(May 2023 - Ongoing)

- Responsible for overlooking and aiding a board of 30 campus organizations across Southern California to achieve organizational goals.
- Worked alongside the U.S. Department of Education and District Attorney to address and combat discrimination on University campuses.
- Organized and managed large-scaled conferences for college students, addressing real student needs and interests.
- Facilitated regional meetings and initiatives, driving collective efforts, increasing student involvement from the previous year by 20%.

California Ambassador - Charity Week

(February 2023 - Ongoing)

- Regional lead responsible for managing fundraising campaign efforts with affiliated organizations across
 California to raise funds for orphaned children in developing countries.
- Contributed to raising \$2.4 million for relief in 19 countries.
- Formulated strategic planning with participating organizations, facilitating their success in fundraising.
- Recruited additional organizations to affiliate with Charity Week, amplifying reach and impact.

Youth Director – Islamic Society of Corona Society

(June 2022 – Ongoing)

- Lead in designing engaging educational and spiritual programs for local youth.
- Provided tailored professional development support to enhance skills and career growth.
- Developed and honed essential project management skills alongside a professional staff.
- Delegated and orchestrated committees to efficiently coordinate larger-scale events.

EDUCATION

University of California, Riverside

(Expected June 2024)